

Personal Info

tylerkm75@gmail.com



(256) 469-5783

Education

 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
Idaho State University
2017 - 2021
Graduated with Honors
Distinction

Skills

Python (including Django)

Ansible

Openshift

Red Hat Enterprise Linux

JBOSS EAP

C# (including ASP .NET Core)

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB

PHP, JavaScript

Tyler Kness-Miller

Principal Linux Systems Engineer

Summary

Skilled Linux Administrator with 5+ years of experience in Linux based systems. Expert in automating critical enterprise workflows using Ansible and Python, and a wide range of experiences with Openshift and disconnected environments. Active TS/SCI Clearance with polygraph.

Work Experience

Principal Systems Engineer, ECS Federal, Pocatello, Huntsville, AL April 2020 - Present

- Led the introduction and deployment of Ansible Automation Platform on multiple disconnected environments.
 - I was instrumental in onboarding and kick starting the adoption of Ansible across multiple teams with a wide variety of different infrastructure devices and services, including Windows servers, Cisco network devices, custom in-house application servers, and storage arrays.
- I developed multiple Ansible workflows to almost completely automate the process of baselining, maintaining, troubleshooting, and decommissioning Linux servers.
 - I demonstrated a complete auto-remediation workflow to resolve common Linux server issues using Zabbix and Dynatrace as the monitoring tools, Event Driven Ansible to handle incoming events and start AAP workflows, and Jira for automatic reporting and ticket creation.
 - I also automated the process of deploying and configuring JBOSS Enterprise Application Platform on a Linux server using Ansible.
- Led an initiative to develop a custom RHEL baseline that was 97% compliant with DISA STIG guidelines.
 - I engineered, demonstrated, and deployed a custom solution using CI/CD pipelines (GitLab Runner) and Ansible to automate the creation and deployment of these custom baseline images as changes to its underlying kickstart files and package requirements are made.
- Engineered a custom solution to allow developers to write code on unclassified networks while automatically propagating said changes to instances on classified networks using existing cross-domain solutions.

- I designed and deployed a custom developer virtual desktop image on VMWare Horizon to allow development of internal applications and helm charts.
 - I also demonstrated a custom Ansible workflow to update the master desktop image, take a snapshot, and deploy the new updated image using Horizon's REST API.
- I led the testing and deployment of several Openshift clusters on vSphere-backed infrastructure. These clusters include the deployment of OpenID Connect, Openshift Virtualization, and GitLab/GitLab Runner with custom SCC contexts to allow operability.

Student Workforce Trainee, US Department of Justice, Pocatello, ID June 2019 - February 2020

- Led the deployment of a disconnected repository manager to manage PyPi/Maven/npm mirrors for development on a disconnected network.
- I developed the team's first instance of a server inventory webpage to aggregate and display server data from multiple sources.

Certifications

Red Hat Certified Engineer

June 2023

Red Hat Certified System Administrator

March 2021